<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SecLinux Blog</title>
    <link>https://seclinux.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SecLinux Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:30:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seclinux.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bindcompilation</title>
      <link>https://seclinux.net/posts/bindcompilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seclinux.net/posts/bindcompilation/</guid>
      <description>Bind Stable Compilation In this article I will document the process of compiling ISC Bind 9.18.21 from source on a Rocky Linux 8 minimal install host.
In order to compile Bind 9.18.21 on Rocky Linux minimal install host you must first install many dependencies. You must first install a C compiler and the gnu autotools. The rest of the dependencies may be installed from Rocky package repository but some must be installed and compiled from source.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;bind-stable-compilation&#34;&gt;Bind Stable Compilation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article I will document the process of compiling ISC Bind 9.18.21 from source on a Rocky Linux 8 minimal install host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to compile Bind 9.18.21 on Rocky Linux minimal install host you must first install many dependencies.  You must first install a C compiler and the gnu autotools.  The rest of the dependencies may be installed from Rocky package repository but some must be installed and compiled from source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dependecies are the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libuv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;liburcu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libxml2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libnghttp2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;json-c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lmdb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protobuf-c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fstrm-devel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These dependencies are required when compiling Bind the following way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;./configure --prefix&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/opt/bind9 --enable-developer --enable-warn-error --enable-dnstap --enable-singletrace --enable-querytrace --enable-full-report --with-lmdb --with-libxml2 --with-json-c --disable-fips-mode --with-libnghttp2  --enable-fixed-rrset
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Rig</title>
      <link>https://seclinux.net/posts/myrig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 01:03:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seclinux.net/posts/myrig/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I thought I would give a brief overview of my development/learning environment. Many of my wacky experiments are going to be done on a rig I built in 2022. In 2022, I was working as a cybersec consultant and decided to build a rig that would help me with what I was working on at the time. Mostly, I was going to be running many simultaneous VMs in complex topologies and running DDoS mitigation experiments on them.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I would give a brief overview of my development/learning environment.  Many of my wacky experiments are going to be done on a rig I built in 2022. In 2022, I was working as a cybersec consultant and decided to build a rig that would help me with what I was working on at the time.  Mostly, I was going to be running many simultaneous VMs in complex topologies and running DDoS mitigation experiments on them.  I required a lot of memory and decent CPU, GPU was not a priority at the time so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get an expensive GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hardware&#34;&gt;The Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered the parts from many different places I will not be posting the BOM here I will be posting the inxi output of the machine.  The experiments done here can be done on any machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;symtex@hypervisor:~$ sudo inxi -b
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;System:    Host: hypervisor.seclinux.net Kernel: 5.15.0-79-generic x86_64 bits: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;64&lt;/span&gt; Console: tty &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;           Distro: Ubuntu 20.04.6 LTS &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Focal Fossa&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Machine:   Type: Desktop Mobo: ASUSTeK model: TUF GAMING X570-PLUS &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;WI-FI&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; v: Rev X.0x serial: xxxxxxxxxxxxxxx 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;           BIOS: American Megatrends v: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;4204&lt;/span&gt; date: 02/25/2022 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;CPU:       16-Core: AMD Ryzen &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; 5950X type: MT MCP speed: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;2199&lt;/span&gt; MHz min/max: 2200/3400 MHz 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Graphics:  Device-1: NVIDIA GK208B &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;GeForce GT 730&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; driver: nvidia v: 470.199.02 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;           Display: server: X.org 1.20.13 driver: nvidia unloaded: fbdev,modesetting,nouveau,vesa tty: 140x34 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;           Message: Advanced graphics data unavailable in console &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; root. 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Network:   Device-1: Intel Wireless-AC &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;9260&lt;/span&gt; driver: iwlwifi 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;           Device-2: Realtek RTL8111/8168/8411 PCI Express Gigabit Ethernet driver: r8169 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drives:    Local Storage: total: 2.27 TiB used: 223.63 GiB &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;9.6%&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Info:      Processes: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;428&lt;/span&gt; Uptime: 1h 43m Memory: 125.70 GiB used: 1.04 GiB &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;0.8%&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; Init: systemd runlevel: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; Shell: bash 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;           inxi: 3.0.38 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-software&#34;&gt;The software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to use Ubuntu 20.04 Focal Fossa not the latest LTS 22.04.  I do this for stability reasons and availability of documentation.  In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Debian as the distro of choice for my home servers/rigs but this time I wanted to use Ubuntu mate.  I decided to use Ubuntu mate because it provides a modern kernel to support modern hardware and modern graphics cards.  Ubuntu mate also has a great looking classic UI that I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I connect to the rig via SSH and x2go if I need a graphical application that requires much memory/CPU (last time it was ghidra).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kvm-libvirt-and-ovs&#34;&gt;KVM, libvirt, and OVS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to spinning up the necessary environments I like to use Vanilla KVM/libvirt with OpenVSwitch.  I know there are higher level abstraction tools like eve-ng, gns3, openstack, etc etc.  I prefer this setup because I feel I have manual control of all aspects of virtualization this helps me at time of debugging.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firstpost</title>
      <link>https://seclinux.net/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 22:41:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seclinux.net/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>About this blog This is my first post. I decided to start this blog to share my technical findinds and general thoughts on a wide range of topics. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the technical content found on this page can perhaps help someone out there who is looking for answers. The topics discussed in this blog include the following:
FOSS Computer Science IP Networking Software Development MIS/DevOps CyberSecurity Retro Computing Misc About me My name is David Farje.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-blog&#34;&gt;About this blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post.  I decided to start this blog to share my technical findinds and general thoughts on a wide range of topics. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the technical content found on this page can perhaps help someone out there who is looking for answers. The topics discussed in this blog include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IP Networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIS/DevOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CyberSecurity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retro Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is David Farje. I was born in 1982. My first computer was a i386 based IBM/PC clone in 1989.  The operating system was MS-DOS, the game was called &amp;ldquo;Digger&amp;rdquo;.  My first experience coding (1993) was QBasic and simple programs in Turbo C++. In my Windows era I briefly used Visual Basic 6.0. I discovered Linux in 1997 and began the adoption process. By 2003 I was confident in all Linux system administration aspects and running it on all my machines.  In 2005 I  started working as systems administrator then turned to network engineering and cybersecurity. The whole time I was passionate about FOSS.  It was great but I always felt like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really contributing to the development of the field.  It&amp;rsquo;s a field that has given me so much and today I would like to contribute to the FOSS movement in a meaningful way.  This blog is part of that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
