<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>first on SecLinux Blog</title>
    <link>https://seclinux.net/tags/first/</link>
    <description>Recent content in first on SecLinux Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 22:41:54 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seclinux.net/tags/first/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Firstpost</title>
      <link>https://seclinux.net/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 22:41:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seclinux.net/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post. I decided to start this blog as a way to publish the technical notes that I write down in markdown. I work as a network and cybersecurity engineer with a background in coding. I spent many years running networks and datacenters, due to this I have accumulated lots of knowledge in Linux Systems Administration and networks. The blog will also contain my general opinion on various topics.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This is my first post.  I decided to start this blog as a way to publish the technical notes that I write down in markdown.  I work as a network and cybersecurity engineer with a background in coding.  I spent many years running networks and datacenters, due to this I have accumulated lots of knowledge in Linux Systems Administration and networks.  The blog will also contain my general opinion on various topics.  It is however, mostly a covering the following topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIS/DevOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CyberSecurity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my hope to contribute some literature in these topics and it is my ultimate hope that these articles will help others out there who want to learn about these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
