<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>introduction on SecLinux Blog</title>
    <link>https://dfarje.github.io/tags/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in introduction on SecLinux Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 22:41:54 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dfarje.github.io/tags/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Firstpost</title>
      <link>https://dfarje.github.io/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 22:41:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dfarje.github.io/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>About this blog This is my first post. I decided to start this blog to share my technical findinds and general thoughts on a wide range of topics. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the technical content found on this page can perhaps help someone out there who is looking for answers. The topics discussed in this blog include the following:
FOSS Computer Science IP Networking Software Development MIS/DevOps CyberSecurity Retro Computing Misc About me My name is David Farje.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-blog&#34;&gt;About this blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post.  I decided to start this blog to share my technical findinds and general thoughts on a wide range of topics. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the technical content found on this page can perhaps help someone out there who is looking for answers. The topics discussed in this blog include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IP Networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIS/DevOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CyberSecurity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retro Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is David Farje. I was born in 1982. My first computer was a i386 based IBM/PC clone in 1989.  The operating system was MS-DOS, the game was called &amp;ldquo;Digger&amp;rdquo;.  My first experience coding (1993) was QBasic and simple programs in Turbo C++. In my Windows era I briefly used Visual Basic 6.0. I discovered Linux in 1997 and began the adoption process. By 2003 I was confident in all Linux system administration aspects and running it on all my machines.  In 2005 I  started working as systems administrator then turned to network engineering and cybersecurity. The whole time I was passionate about FOSS.  It was great but I always felt like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really contributing to the development of the field.  It&amp;rsquo;s a field that has given me so much and today I would like to contribute to the FOSS movement in a meaningful way.  This blog is part of that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
