<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>introduction on SecLinux Blog</title>
    <link>https://seclinux.net/tags/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in introduction on SecLinux Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 22:41:54 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seclinux.net/tags/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Firstpost</title>
      <link>https://seclinux.net/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 22:41:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seclinux.net/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>About this blog This is my first post. I decided to start this blog as a way to publish the technical notes that I write down in markdown, I believe in open and simple text formats as a way to generate content that has more resilience against bit rot. I will be using hugo to compile the notes into HTML.
FOSS Computer Science IP Networking Software Development MIS/DevOps CyberSecurity Retro Computing Misc I&amp;rsquo;m mostly writing this blog to document my own learning process.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-blog&#34;&gt;About this blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post.  I decided to start this blog as a way to publish the technical notes that I write down in markdown, I believe in open and simple text formats as a way to generate content that has more resilience against bit rot. I will be using hugo to compile the notes into HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IP Networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIS/DevOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CyberSecurity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retro Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m mostly writing this blog to document my own learning process.  In the past I have kept notes in various proprietary formats which made it harder for me to switch to other note taking or documentation solutions.  If I&amp;rsquo;m lucky I will have the priviledge of educating someone out there who is looking for the information I post here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is David no fancy aliases just @symtex.  I work as a network and cybersecurity engineer with a background in coding.  I spent many years deploying/operating/automating/securing networks and datacenters for many customers in Latin America some in USA and Europe.  I been toying around with Linux and networking since I was 14 years old.  I&amp;rsquo;m 40 at the time of this writing so you know I have a few stories to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
